<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Time is Flying and other lines written in the Bay of Lerici</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>Shelley-Godwin Archive edition, <date>2017</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <distributor>University of Maryland</distributor>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>
                        <ref target="http://www.shelleygodwinarchive.org/">http://www.shelleygodwinarchive.org/</ref>
                    </addrLine>
                </address>
                <availability status="free">
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">
                        <p>CC0 1.0 Universal.</p>
                        <p> To the extent possible under law, the creators of the metadata records for the Shelley-Godwin Archive 
                            have waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this work.</p>
                    </licence>
                </availability>
                <pubPlace>Oxford, UK, and College Park, MD</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>MS Shelley Adds C 4
                        <altIdentifier>
                            <idno></idno>
                        </altIdentifier>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem> class="poem">
                            <bibl status="draft">
							Contains two, potentially three works: “Bright wanderer” (lines 1-6 on page 78), 
							“Lines written in the Bay of Lerici (lines 7 on page 78 through page 81),” and 
							“Time is Flying” (82). A single line from the final page of The Triumph of Life (page 113) 
                                   is included but not entirely rendered because one line pertains to “Time is Flying.” 
							The first time “Lines” was published, by Richard Garnett in Macmillan’s Magazine in 1862, 
							the first six lines, which we’ll continue to refer to as “Bright wanderer,” 
							were omitted but included as a detached fragment titled “To the Moon.”
                                <author>Percy Bysshe Shelley</author>
						  <title>Lines Written in the Bay of Lerici</title>
                            </bibl>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
					<physDesc>
						<objectDesc>
						<supportDesc>
							<collation>Entirely written on a single autonomous bifolium of Parodi paper (ff. 35–36), 
							with no sign of blots offset from other bifolia. The writing takes up nearly four sides, 
                                   but as there is blank space sufficient for a line or two at the foot of f. 36v, 
							we may infer that it did not continue onto a lost leaf.</collation>
							<foliation>The bifolium is firmly folded in two horizontally, unlike the other leaves in Triumph MS, 
							and is at present placed between part of Supplement 5 and “Time is flying,” but this placement 
                                   is very questionable. Reiman concluded that the folios had been numbered arbitrarily on their 
                                   accessioning at the Bodleian, perhaps following their state at reception, and that it was 
                                   “impossible to determine exactly when during the composition of TL Shelley wrote [‘Lines’].” 
                                   It is a fair guess that “Bright wanderer” was written after both 
							“Time is flying” and To Jane.</foliation>
						</supportDesc>
						</objectDesc> 
						<handDesc>
							<handNote xml:id="pbs">
                                 <persName>Percy Shelley</persName>
							</handNote>
								<handNote xml:id="pbs1" medium="pencil">
                                        <persName>Percy Shelley</persName>
                                </handNote>
						</handDesc>
					</physDesc>
					</msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <sourceDoc>
        <xi:include href="ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4-0078.xml" />
        <xi:include href="ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4-0079.xml" />
        <xi:include href="ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4-0080.xml" />
        <xi:include href="ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4-0081.xml" />
        <xi:include href="ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4-0113.xml" />
    </sourceDoc>
</TEI>
